Inventory of the Charles Francis Sloane papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Charles Francis Sloane papers
1940-1991
2010C1
Hoover Institution Archives
14 manuscript boxes, 4 oversize boxes, 1 oversize folder (11.6 linear feet)
The Charles Francis Sloane papers consist of scrapbooks, writings, correspondence, public safety publications, photographs, slides, and other materials that primarily relate to police training, counter-insurgency warfare, and South Vietnamese police activities during the Vietnam War.
Sloane, Charles Francis, 1910-
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2009.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1910 Born, Pennsylvania
1931-1942 Trooper, New York State Police, Oneida, NY
1942-1945 Civilian Chief of Police (Patrol Supervisor), US Naval Training Station, US Navy Department, Sampson, NY
1946-1949 Chief of Police, Cortland, NY
1949-1955 Senior Personnel Technician, Examinations Division, New York State Department of Civil Service, Albany, NY
1955 Organized the Vietnamese National Police Academy
1955-1960 Police Advisor, Michigan State University Viet Nam Advisory Group, Saigon, Vietnam
1960-1962 Police Administrator, Syracuse, NY
1962-1973 Worked for the United States State Department (Agency for International Development)
1962-1964 Regional Police Advisor, Region 1, Vietnam
1965-1966 Deputy Chief of Field Operations, Saigon, Vietnam
1966-1967 Assistant Coordinator of VN Affairs, Washington, D.C.
1967-1969 Provincial Public Safety Chief, Dacca, East Pakistan
1969-1971 Deputy Assistant Public Safety Officer (Field Operations), Vietnam
1971-1973 Training Advisor/Inspections (Saigon) and Regional Training Advisor (Can Tho), Vietnam
1973-? Instructor/Administrative Officer, Management Systems Section, International Police Academy
Scope and Content of Collection
The Charles Francis Sloane papers consist of scrapbooks, writings, correspondence, public safety publications, photographs, slides, and other materials that primarily relate to police training, counter-insurgency warfare, and South Vietnamese police activities during the Vietnam War.
The scrapbooks primarily document Sloane’s experiences in numerous positions throughout New York State and his work for the United States State Department Agency for International Development (AID). The remainder of the collection documents Sloane’s work experience in public safety in Vietnam. Many photographs and documents reveal events surrounding public safety training and recognition ceremonies. More specifically, numerous photographs relate to United States Operations Mission (USOM), Vietnam, the Joint United States Public Affairs Office (JUSPAO), and dinner receptions.
Materials are arranged in chronological order or by the original order of the creator.
Police training.; Guerrilla warfare.; Police--Vietnam.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975.
- Career File, 1942-1991 (Boxes 1-3)
  Scope and Contents note
  Contains career-related material, including employment documentation, correspondence, personnel records, certificates of recognition, agendas, rosters, reports, memoranda, photographs, handwritten notes, documents about Buddhist incidents, police documents, a daily log, two interviews on microfilm, and identification items primarily used during Sloane's time working for New York State and the Agency for International Development (AID) in Vietnam.
  The series also includes documents about Sloane's involvement in Santa Barbara County as a student at Santa Barbara City College and as a member of a photo club and the Board of Directors of Senior Programs of Santa Barbara. Professional records are primarily composed of police training records, directories, listings, resumes, rosters, glossaries, notes, syllabi, agendas, and related records pertaining to Sloane’s profession.
  - New York State scrapbook, 1942-1958 (Box-folder 1: 1)
    Scrapbook is composed of Sloane’s reports, correspondence, news clippings, personnel records, certificates of recognition, writings, and examination records.
  - Agency for International Development (AID) scrapbook, 1962-1974 (Box-folder 1: 2)
    Scrapbook is primarily composed of personnel records, performance evaluations, requests for official travel, identification cards, news clippings, correspondence, resumes, memoranda, certificates of recognition, position descriptions, school reports, and notices.
  - Santa Barbara County scrapbook, 1973-1981, 1984 (Box-folder 1: 3)
    Scrapbook is primarily composed of certificates of recognition, advertisements, correspondence, identification cards, grade reports, news clippings, and personal qualification statements.
  - Miscellaneous scrapbooks, 1955-1971 (Box-folder 1: 4)
    Scrapbooks are primarily composed of certificates of recognition, news clippings, memoranda, correspondence, invitations, and an evaluation form that pertains to Sloane's news articles, receptions with important persons, and his profession.
  - Miscellaneous scrapbooks, 1958-1966 (Box-folder 1: 5)
    Scrapbooks are primarily composed of memoranda, correspondence, notification of personnel action forms, photographs, requests for travel, documents pertaining to the Agency for International Development (AID), resumes, news clippings, and certificates of recognition that pertain to Sloane's profession.
  - Miscellaneous scrapbooks, 1966-1973 (Box-folder 1: 6)
    Scrapbooks are primarily composed of photographs, requests for travel, notification of personnel action forms, certificates of recognition, correspondence, performance evaluation reports, memoranda, end-of-tour reports, and descriptions of duties that pertain to Sloane's profession.
  - "Survey of Police Training Centers in Malaya and Thailand (From July 1 to July 12, 1957)," report (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - Professional records, 1961 (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - Post reports, 1961 March 27 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - "Daily Log of Regional Police Advisor Hue," bound volume, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 1: 10)
    Contains descriptions of initial Buddist protests.
  - Final Report Covering Activities of the Michigan State University Vietnam Advisory Group for the Period May 2-, 1955 - June 30, 1962 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - Professional records, circa 1963 (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - Buddhist incidents documents, 1963 (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - Handwritten notices, 1963 (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - Miscellaneous documents, circa 1964, undated (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - Voluntary firearms training documents, circa 1964 (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - Alvin M. Strand documents, 1964-1966 (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - Professional records, 1964 (Box-folder 2: 8)
  - End-of-tour reports, 1964 (Box-folder 2: 9)
  - Professional records, 1965 (Box-folder 2: 10)
  - Performance evaluation reports, 1965 (Box-folder 2: 11)
  - Performance evaluation reports, 1966 (Box-folder 2: 12)
  - End-of-tour reports, 1966 (Box-folder 2: 13-14)
  - Professional records, 1966 (Box-folder 2: 15)
  - Status reports, 1968 (Box-folder 2: 16)
  - East Pakistan documents, 1968 (Box-folder 2: 17)
  - Professional records, 1968 (Box-folder 2: 18)
  - Performance evaluation reports, 1968 (Box-folder 2: 19)
  - Professional records, 1969 (Box-folder 2: 20)
  - Performance evaluation reports, 1969 (Box-folder 2: 21)
  - Interviews, RAND Corporation, microfilm, 1969 (Box-folder 2: 22)
  - Handwritten notes, circa 1970 (Box-folder 2: 23)
  - Professional records, 1970 (Box-folder 2: 24-25)
  - Performance evaluation reports, 1970 (Box-folder 2: 26)
  - End-of-tour reports, 1970 (Box-folder 2: 27)
  - Program Review Book II, 1970 (Box-folder 3: 1-2)
  - Performance evaluation reports, 1971 (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - Professional records, 1971 (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - Directorate General of National Police (DGNP) documents related to visit of Sir Robert Thompson (Mr. Rhoades), 1971 (Box-folder 3: 5)
    Includes declassified records returned to file after January 2016 release by Hoover.
  - Completion of assignment reports, 1972 (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - Performance evaluation reports, 1972 (Box-folder 3: 7)
  - Police officer graduation ceremony, Chuong Trinh program, 1972 (Box-folder 3: 8)
  - Inspection report (two copies), 1972 (Box-folder 3: 9)
  - Professional records, 1973 (Box-folder 3: 10)
  - Performance evaluation ratings, 1974 (Box-folder 3: 11)
  - Handwritten notes, 1974 (Box-folder 3: 12)
  - Professional records, 1974 (Box-folder 3: 13)
  - A Brief History of Vietnam to 1960, manuscript, 1979 (Box-folder 3: 14)
  - South-East Asia and Its Impact on the Khmer Civilization, manuscript for Archaeology 1, 1980 (Box-folder 3: 15)
  - Handwritten notes, 1991 (Box-folder 3: 16)
  - Handwritten notes, undated (Box-folder 3: 17)
  - Professional records, undated (Box-folder 3: 18)
- Public Safety Materials, 1940-1982 (Boxes 3-6)
  Contains materials related to public safety, including articles from magazines and journals, policies, manuals, newsletters, reports, lectures, legal documents, bulletins, brochures, and booklets.
  - "The New York State Police," The Outpost, 1940 (Box-folder 3: 19)
  - Policy Governing the Traffic on Public Highway and Services of Transporation by Commercial Motor Vehicles (two copies), 1946 (Box-folder 3: 20)
  - "Is This a New Police Weapon?," The Conference News, 1948 (Box-folder 3: 21)
  - Police articles in journals, 1954, 1955 (Box-folder 3: 22)
  - NP Academy Manual, 1955 (Box-folder 3: 23)
  - Table of Contents and "Police Science Book Reviews," The Journal of Criminal Law, Criminology, and Police Science, 1955 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - Michigan Police Journal, 1956 (Box-folder 4: 2)
  - The Chieftain, newsletters, 1956 (Box-folder 4: 3)
  - Report on the Proposed Organization of the Law Enforcement Agencies of The Republic of Viet-Nam, 1956 (Box-folder 4: 4)
  - Lectures given at The Civil Guard High Officers School and National Police Academy, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 4: 5)
  - Lectures given at The Civil Guard High Officers School, 1957 (Box-folder 4: 6)
  - History of Michigan State University's Police Project in Viet Nam, report, circa 1957 (Box-folder 4: 7)
  - Michigan Police Journal, 1957 (Box-folder 4: 8)
  - The Police Chief, magazines, 1958 (Box-folder 4: 9-10)
  - Police Communications Project, report, 1958 (Box-folder 4: 11)
  - The Police Chief, magazine, 1958 (Box-folder 4: 12)
    In Chinese, with a translation of Sloane's article.
  - Traffic Stop Signs, booklet/pamphlet, circa 1959 (Box-folder 4: 13)
  - Gil Hebard Guns, brochure, 1959, 1960 (Box-folder 4: 14)
  - Penal Code of Central Viet Nam, legal document, 1960s (Box-folder 4: 15)
  - The FBI Practical Pistol Course and Narcotics and Dangerous Drugs, bulletins, 1960s-1970s (Box-folder 4: 16)
  - Manual about National Police registering citizens of the Republic of Vietnam, 1960s (Box-folder 4: 17)
  - Revolver Firing in Darkness Manual, circa 1960 (Box-folder 4: 18)
  - The Police Chief, magazine, 1960 (Box-folder 4: 19)
  - The Carbine Technical Manual and Revolver Marksmanship Manual, 1962 (Box-folder 5: 1-2)
  - The National Police of the Central Highlands Region of Vietnam, report, 1962 (Box-folder 5: 3)
  - Public Safety Code 710, brochure, circa 1962 (Box-folder 5: 4)
  - Methods of Presenting Supervisory Training Manual, circa 1963 (Box-folder 5: 5)
  - Marlin Guns for 1963, brochure (Box-folder 5: 6)
  - Police Training Ranges Manual Addendum cover sheet and The Public Safety Program Vietnam, 1964 (Box-folder 5: 7)
  - Commander's Word, newsletters, circa 1965 (Box-folder 5: 8)
  - An Interesting Case by The National Police, booklets, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 5: 9)
  - The National Police and Public Safety, reports, 1966 (Box-folder 5: 10-11)
  - Indexing Vietnamese Names, booklet/pamphlet, 1967 (Box-folder 5: 12)
  - Vietnamese manual, 1968 (Box-folder 5: 13)
  - "Internal Security - East Pakistan," conference paper, 1968 (Box-folder 5: 14)
  - Traffic Codes Manual, 1969 (Box-folder 5: 15)
  - Monthly reports, 1969 (Box-folder 5: 16)
  - Vietnamese booklets, circa 1970-1975 (Box-folder 5: 17)
  - National Police Project report, 1970 (Box-folder 5: 18)
  - Techniques of Instruction Manual, 1970 (Box-folder 5: 19)
  - An Tri Handbook: Protection of the People from Terrorism, circa 1970 (Box-folder 5: 20)
  - Vietnamese manual, 1970 (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - Report on the National Police Republic of Vietnam and National Policewomen Report, 1971 (Box-folder 6: 2-3)
  - Vietnamese booklet, 1971 (Box-folder 6: 4)
  - Vietnamese manuals, 1972 (Box-folder 6: 5)
  - International Police Academy lecture, 1973 (Box-folder 6: 6)
  - The Public Safety Newsletter, 1979, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 6: 7-8)
  - Judicial Police and Rights of Citizens, legal document, undated (Box-folder 6: 9)
  - Ruger Revolvers, brochure, undated (Box-folder 6: 10)
  - Penal Procedures and The Court System, legal documents, undated (Box-folder 6: 11-12)
- Vietnam Materials, 1946-1974 (Boxes 6-9)
  Contains materials related to Vietnam and not directly about public safety. These items include reports, news clippings, journals, bulletins, newsletters, magazines, statistical yearbook, papers, manuals, books, booklets/pamphlets, handbooks, and briefing folders.
  - United States Operations Mission to Vietnam, reports, 1954-1957 (Box-folder 6: 13)
  - Vietnamese report, 1957 (Box-folder 6: 14)
  - Preliminary Research Report on the PMS, 1957 (Box-folder 6: 15)
  - News clippings, 1957, 1963, 1975, 1984 (Box-folder 6: 16)
  - Vietnamese journal, 1959 (Box-folder 7: 1)
  - "Corruption Understood by GNP," report, 1960s (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - How to Conceal Weapons and Documents, bulletin, 1960s (Box-folder 7: 3)
  - Vietnamese newsletter, 1960 (Box-folder 7: 4)
  - Vietnam news clippings, 1962 (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - Military officials poster, 1963 (Map case)
  - Articles from United-Press International, circa 1964 (Box-folder 7: 6)
  - A Report on Counterinsurgency Operations in Malaya and Their Relevance to the Problem in South Vietnam, 1964 (Box-folder 7: 7)
  - Report on North Viet Nam Aggression Against South and Refugee Control Activies Quang Ngai Province Republic of Viet Nam, reports, 1965 (Box-folder 7: 8-9)
  - Post Report, 1966 (Box-folder 7: 10)
  - Time news clipping, 1967 (Box-folder 7: 11)
  - Pacific Stars & Stripes Sunday Magazine, 1968 May 5 (Box-folder 7: 12)
  - Vietnam Statistical Yearbook, 1968 (Box-folder 7: 13)
  - Vietnam: Lessons and Mislessons, report, 1969 (Box-folder 7: 14)
  - Pacific Stars and Stripes Sunday Magazine, 1969 July 13 (Box-folder 7: 15)
  - The New Statute on Agricultural Cooperatives in the Context of the Agricultural Policy Debate in North Viet Nam: A Background Paper, 1969 October (Box-folder 7: 16)
  - The Crop Growing Season Climates of South Viet-Nam, report, 1969 May 15 (Box-folder 7: 17)
  - Lessons from the Vietnam War: Report of a Seminar Held at the Royal United Service Institution (two copies), 1969 February 12 (Box-folder 7: 18)
  - "Special 'Tet' Edition, Employees' Bulletin,", circa 1970, 1973 (Box-folder 7: 19)
  - Vietnamese manual, 1970 (Box-folder 7: 20)
  - Vietnamese book, circa 1970 (Box-folder 7: 21)
  - Basic Course Student Notebook, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 1-3)
  - The Viet-Cong Strategy of Terror, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 4)
  - Kien Giang Province, An Giang, Kien Hoa Province, Phong Dinh, and Bac Lieu briefing folders, 1971 (Box-folder 8: 5)
  - Wireless Bulletin, 1971 April 19 (Box-folder 8: 6)
  - The President and Vice President of the Republic of Vietnam, booklet/pamphlet, 1971 (Box-folder 8: 7)
  - The Vietnamese Village Handbook for Advisors, 1971 (Box-folder 8: 8)
  - Cultural Receptivity to Induced Administrative Change: The Case of Vietnam: A Test of an Anthropological Framework for Cross-Cultural Transfer of Administrative Features, 1971 (Box-folder 8: 9)
    Prepared for the Joint Meeting of the SEADAG Development Administration and Political Development Panels.
  - Public Information Series Bureau of Public Affairs, bulletin, 1971 (Box-folder 8: 10)
  - An Xuyen, Chau Doc, and Dinh Tuong briefing folders, circa 1971, 1972 (Box-folder 8: 11)
  - Drac and Chuong Thien Province fact books, 1972 (Box-folder 8: 12)
  - Kien Tuong, Ba Xuyen, and Vinh Long briefing folders, 1972 (Box-folder 8: 13)
  - Judicial invest(?) training manual, prepared at Go Cong Province, 1972 (Box-folder 8: 14)
  - Vietnamese fact book, 1973 (Box-folder 8: 15)
  - Restoring Peace in Viet-Nam: Basic Documents on Ending the War and Restoring Peace in Viet-Nam, booklet (two copies), circa 1973 (Box-folder 9: 1)
  - "Ceasefire Agreement," CORDS/DRAC Information Bulletin, 1973 (Box-folder 9: 2)
  - British Information Services news releases, 1973 (Box-folder 9: 3)
  - Vietnam Report: "Not in Vain," based on an independent fact-finding mission to South Vietnam, 1974 (Box-folder 9: 4)
  - Viet-Nam Reporter: The United World Mission, United Welfare and Relief Services newsletter, 1974 (Box-folder 9: 5)
  - Vietnamese motorcycles poster, undated (Box-folder 9: 6)
  - "In Praise of America," editorial, undated (Box-folder 9: 7)
  - National Order of Vietnam medals booklet, undated (Box-folder 9: 8)
  - "Squaring the Error," Foreign Affairs Journal (two copies), undated (Box-folder 9: 9)
- Memoranda, 1954-1973 (Box 9)
  About police work, monthly reports, and Vietnam.
  - 1954 (Box-folder 9: 10)
  - 1962 (Box-folder 9: 11)
  - 1963 (Box-folder 9: 12)
  - 1964 (Box-folder 9: 13-14)
  - 1965 (Box-folder 9: 15-16)
  - 1968 (Box-folder 9: 17)
  - 1969 (Box-folder 9: 18)
  - 1970 (Box-folder 9: 19)
  - 1971 (Box-folder 9: 20-21)
  - 1972 (Box-folder 9: 22)
  - 1973 (Box-folder 9: 23)
- Correspondence, 1955-1984 (Boxes 9-10)
  Covers Sloane’s police news articles, the Agency for International Development (AID), Vietnam, Pakistan, insurance policies, the National Police, and public safety.
  - 1955 (Box-folder 9: 24)
  - 1958 (Box-folder 9: 25)
  - 1962 (Box-folder 9: 26)
  - 1963 (Box-folder 9: 27)
  - 1964 (Box-folder 9: 28)
  - 1965 (Box-folder 9: 29)
  - 1968 (Box-folder 9: 30)
  - 1969 (Box-folder 9: 31)
  - 1970 (Box-folder 10: 1)
  - 1971 (Box-folder 10: 2)
  - 1972 (Box-folder 10: 3)
  - 1973 (Box-folder 10: 4)
  - 1974 (Box-folder 10: 5)
  - 1977 (Box-folder 10: 6)
  - 1984 (Box-folder 10: 7)
  - undated (Box-folder 10: 8)
- Photographs, 1955-1972 (Boxes 10-15)
  Includes descriptions, loose photographs, a scrapbook about narcotics, and photographs in albums with captions. Photographs show Vietnam police activities, incidents in Vietnam, and dinner receptions.
  - Vietnam police training, circa 1955 (Box-folder 10: 9-19)
  - National Police ceremony, circa 1955 (Box-folder 10: 20)
  - Vehicles, circa 1955 (Box-folder 10: 21)
  - Military in action, circa 1955 (Box-folder 10: 22)
  - Native Moi village, 1956 (Box-folder 10: 23)
  - Graduating class, 1956 (Box-folder 10: 24)
  - Evaluation team, 1957 (Box-folder 10: 25)
  - Vietnam police training, 1962 (Box-folder 10: 26)
  - Hue images of houses, 1963 (Box-folder 10: 27)
  - Buddhist gets burned, circa 1963 (Box-folder 10: 28)
  - Photograph descriptions, 1963, 1965 (Box-folder 10: 29)
  - Gift-presentation ceremony, 1965 (Box-folder 10: 30)
  - Buddhist demonstration, 1965 January 22 (Box-folder 10: 31)
  - Boy and Girl Scouts, punishment, troops, 1965 January 24 (Box-folder 10: 32-33)
  - Buddhist Association, 1965 January 26 (Box-folder 10: 34-35)
  - Demonstration, 1965 January 28 (Box-folder 10: 36)
  - Public execution, 1965 January 28 (Box-folder 11: 1)
  - Joint United States Public Affairs Office, circa 1965-1972 (Box-folder 11: 2)
  - Saigon Lions Club award, 1965 (Box-folder 11: 3)
  - Viet Cong bombs, 1965 (Box-folder 11: 4)
  - Sloane in Vietnam for police training, 1966 (Box-folder 11: 5-7)
  - Dong Operation Against Narcotics, scrapbook (two copies), 1971 June 14-18 (Box-folder 11: 8)
  - Animal killings, 1965 (Box-folder 11: 9)
  - Archaeological dig, undated (Box-folder 11: 10-13)
  - Sloane standing next to police officer, Sloane standing next to assumed Vietnamese couple and Caucasian man, undated (Box-folder 11: 14)
  - Vietnamese women recognition event, undated (Box-folder 11: 15)
  - Standing traffic police, undated (Box-folder 11: 16)
  - Mounted police, undated (Box-folder 11: 17)
  - Delhi police, on cardboard, undated (Box-folder 11: 18)
  - National Police Academy, Far Eastern Division, British Security Office, training Saigon municipal police in revolver shooting, unhinged lacquered-wood album, 1955-1957 (Box 12)
  - Reception, dinner, police training, hinged lacquered-wood album, circa 1955-1956 (Box 13)
  - Vietnam police training, narcotics, red album, circa 1965 (Box 14)
  - "V.N. National Police First Annual Pistol National Match," report followed by photos and arrow descriptions, blue album, 1965 (Box 15)
  - "National Police Reception, N.P. HQ," group photograph, 1964 (Box-folder 15: 1)
  - Sloane with Vietnamese troops, circa 1955-1960 (Box-folder 15: 2)
  - Buddhist monks, 1963 (Box-folder 15: 3)
  - Fishermen, 1963 (Box-folder 15: 4)
  - Procession, Quang Ngai Province, 1964 (Box-folder 15: 5)
- Slides, 1955-1973 (Boxes 16-18)
  Slides in order by creator's slide carousel as numbered on dot labels on the original boxes. Notes on each set of slides duplicated from creator's labels on the slide boxes. Some instances have significant detail on sets of slides, while others have more minimal descriptions. The numeric sequence does not include 11-12 and 18-20.
  - 1. Vietnam, 1955 and on, 1955-1960 (Box 16)
    1955-1960, Market Places, etc.; Chinese Dr., 94-95.
  - 2. 1957-1960 (Box 16)
  - 3. Vietnam, 1955-1960 (Box 16)
    Saigon Markets, etc.; Ektachrome Red; Market Places and Various Gardens; 31-36: Watering; 37: Funeral; 44-50: Buddhist Temple; 51: October 26th 1955, Dien-at Freedra, Home of French High Commissioner for China; 61-63: Office Party; 73-74: Funeral; 76-79: Old Chinese Artists; 80-87: Store Merchandise; 88: General-'TET'.
  - 4. Vietnam, 1955-1959 (Box 16)
    1-22: General; 22-44: Thanh Ly workshop, Tu da Mo; 49-53: Trip south to Thu Duc, fishing nets; 54-63: Map St. Jacques, Vung Talk; 64: Ceremony for the 81 dead, Cap St. Jacques.
  - 5. Vietnam, 1955-1959 (Box 16)
    1-16: Orphanage; 18-33: Trip with Shelby to Qui Nhon; 35-93: Trip with Ryan and Vic Stricker Hoach Int. to Ban Mi Thuot, Pleeker, and Kontura-Monteguard. Return via coast and to Cap St. Jacques Police Academy; 94-99: Independence Police Reader and Preach Governor General: China.
  - 6. Vietnam, 1955-1959 (Box 16)
    1: Schools in and around Saigon; 9: Military posts; 10-23: Charlotte and Viet-my pchase and stndrits; 24-25: usual; 26-31: stenos in office; 33-41: Pahi in English classes; 42-60: 1st National Military Pistol, 1959; 61-83: shooting range and jiu jitsu; 84-94: New Pahi Academy.
  - 7. Vietnam, 1955-1959 (Box 16)
    1-10: Dragon Dance; 11-34: Siph Rubber plantation; 36-53: Cao Sai Temple, Tay Nink; 54-77: Crossing River Montaguard territory charcoate; 78-82: Montaguard killing young buffalo, harvest ceremony; 83-96: En route to Dalat, Montaguard slash, kura fire, Pierre's home, market place; 97-100: Chuck's tiger.
  - 8. Vietnam, 1955-1959 (Box 16)